I love it when you pop a V quick. Yeah.
You know, I I always like the opposite
of imposter syndrome. It's like, oh, I'm
a god. You know, for for a split second,
you're like, I'm the best.
Yeah, dude.
>> All right, hackers. I was just looking
into this and I think I figured out how
threat locker elevation control works.
Okay, so when a user launches an
elevated process or they try to threater
agent will hook that into its own
elevation flow. So we don't see any UAC
prompt or anything. the threat locker
admin will be able to grant that process
um elevated permissions for a certain
amount of time or whatever. Very
granular control there. And then the
threat locker agent on the user's device
injects a modified process security
token which will elevate that process
directly. This is awesome because it
avoids things like UAC which um leaves
NLM hashes and stuff like that in memory
right in Elsass.exe.
Um, it creates a timebounded elevation,
right? And it does the elevation to the
process rather than to the user. Really
great stuff. But of course, there's
always like maintenance mode and that
sort of thing if you have to get in
there and do a bunch of administrative
activities. Great stuff by Threat Locker
once again. All right, let's go back to
the show.
So, Packers, we got the this week bug
bounty segment real quick and uh we've
got a couple items here. First one is
that the Adobe team wanted us to let you
know that they are going to be at
Besides London. They're a platinum
sponsor this year and they would like to
meet some of the community out there in
London. So, if you're going to be at
Bside London, drop by, look for people
that uh are wearing Adobe swag and go up
and say, "Hey." Um they'd love to
connect with y'all. Uh the next one up
was this one right here, which is a
hacker 1 report uh on Cloudflare that
recently got disclosed. And I wanted to
shout this out because of how beautiful
this bug is. Um it's entitled bypass of
CloudFare's cache keys and waff via
header overflow. And essentially what
happened here is that uh the attacker
was able to provide a large amount of
headers right 94 in this scenario. Um
and this would overflow the maximum
number of headers for uh Cloudflare's
cache key. And the cache key is the
thing that determines what a unique uh
page is as far as caching goes. And you
can see some of the things that are in
Cloudflare's cache key by by default are
things like the X method override header
H uh XHTP method override header. The
sort of things that will break the back
end probably uh if if they're included,
right? And they shouldn't be cached with
the main asset. But if you were able to
provide one of those after a certain
number of headers that exceeded made it
exceed the max uh number of 100 headers,
including the internal headers added by
Cloudflare, then you would be able to
sneak those in and get your resource
cached with the malicious HTTP method
override key uh or header in there. Um
and that would result in store XSS or
DOSs. Um I just thought this was a
beautiful one to shout out. Uh and I
like man whenever these things pop up on
Hackivity, I'm like wow. uh that's been
sitting there for so long and uh we
could have found that just by sending a
bunch of headers. Um, beautiful. All
right, last but not least, for those of
you on YouTube, you can see that I'm
wearing this sick uh like ugly Christmas
sweater that Whiz sent us. So, I just
wanted to give a shout out to the Whiz
team. Thank you for this beautiful What
is it? It's like Arctic Intelligence uh
you know, AI security ugly Christmas
sweater. So, I'm going to be wearing
this one all holiday season. Thanks,
Whiz team. All right, let's go. Let's
jump into the show.
All righty, man. We're rolling. Happy
Thanksgiving.
>> Yeah, happy Thanksgiving. Uh, and for
some reason, you think that half the
world won't know what that is. Do you
want
>> I don't know, man. I just I mean, it's
it's an American holiday. I don't I
don't think it's a given that that
people will know what that is.
>> Yeah. I feel like that people have
probably heard of it and know what it
is, even if it's not celebrated. But
>> maybe maybe I just feel like I don't
know the holidays for a lot of other
countries, you know?
>> That's fair.
>> Yeah, that's fair. But I guess like a
lot of businesses and stuff do operate
off of like US holidays and stuff like
that. So
>> yeah. So anyways, Thanksgiving is a
holiday where people talk about what
they're thankful for and eat specific
types of food.
>> Yeah. What are you What are you thankful
for this year, man?
>> Oh, that's a great question. Um
>> so it's my first year doing full-time
bug bounty. I think I think I've doubled
my annual goal. So praise God for that.
>> Yeah, it's amazing. So yeah, but uh
outside of that, I think from the
hacking community, I'm like extremely
thankful for, um I guess openness of
information. Like I think that
>> I think that the openness of like
GitHub, for example, has made AI models
incredible at coding. And I just get
benefit from that every single day. And
then and and then I just think in the
hacker community like we didn't have to
develop
um the hacker community didn't have to
develop in such a way where people
wanted to share information. I think all
the time about how people travel to
conferences all over the US for
basically zero pay to share niche
research to like 15 people in a room and
sometimes it blows up but like they're
really excited about it. They've been
prepping all year, dude. Like they've
been working hard in their off hours.
They have a salary job and they're going
to go and present at this conference in
DC to 15 people in a small room about
their little niche area of research.
It's like man the security industry is
really cool in that regard.
>> It is, man. It is. The the dissemination
of information. Yeah, for sure. People
just love talking about it. I think
people are really passionate, you know,
um,
>> which which makes sense. Yeah, dude. I'm
I'm thankful for having you on the team
this this year.
>> Well, thank you.
>> It's been amazing uh to be hosting the
podcast with you. I'm I'm also grateful
for the whole CTB team. They just are
unbelievable. Um, so I know they're
editing it right now. I can I can see
their little stupid smiles. So, thank
you guys for all of your hard work. Um,
and for the CTBB community as well,
dude. like this community is so awesome
because like one of the things we were
thinking about when we we built this
community in the beginning, Joel and I
were like, man, I really wish this
community existed so that we could be a
part of it, you know, and then I'm just
sitting there like in the Discord
reading all the stuff and I'm like, man,
this is great. Like, wait, this is my my
baby. Like, this is so awesome. It
really does feel like you get to like
reap the rewards of the awesome thing
that you built when people are like
sharing novel research, when they're
collaborating, when they're popping
insane bugs, when they're like sharing
their bounties and their success stories
that that community has contributed to,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> I was thinking about that recently, too.
Um, obviously we have a few different
things we're kind of doing for promo for
Thanksgiving and um, and Black Friday
that I want you to mention after I say
this, but I was actually thinking about,
man, how cool it is that we are in an
industry where we get to actually um,
pat the backs of our friends in ways
that are financially meaningful to them
and their family. like me like me and
Douglas Archangel were hacking on a
thing this week and I thought about that
like he got me invited to a you know to
a private challenge or whatever and it
resulted in you know five plus um or I
think it's going to result in five plus
figures of bounties and it's just like
wow that is so cool that I have a friend
who like kind of like shares that type
of um that type of like I don't know
blessing or gift with my family on like
a regular basis. It feels crazy.
>> Yeah, dude. Private program invites or
like challenge invites and stuff like
that are pretty meaningful. Gret me got
me into one the other day and I was
like, "Dang, we crushed this. This is
great. Thanks, man." Like, and and it's
funny for for him as well because, you
know, he was my mentee for like
>> I don't know, a year and a half, two
years, you know, and and then I'm like,
"Yes, I'm reaping the reward of my
>> Exactly."
>> So, and just even small leads though,
like the reason why my mom jumped to
this is because like there's a small
scale of that that happens in our
community in the critical thinkers chat
or in the guild chat where people are
just posting leads and it's like, "Hey,
I think I have a gadget here. Can I turn
into a bug?" And then people are like,
"Oh, here's the buck." And then they
both get paid. And so it's really cool
because it's like a gift to both people
that like had they not had that
connection, nobody would have got paid.
>> Yeah. It's beautiful, too. I mean,
especially in the CT tier, a lot of
people will drop stuff all the time
like, "Hey, you know, how do I solve
this?" And then somebody gives them the
answer and it's like, "Well, that just
paid for 10 years of CTB, you know."
>> Exactly. Yeah. Exactly.
>> All right. Here we go. So, um, yeah.
Well, going back to the Black Friday
thing though, um what we're going to do
just as a part of Black Friday, for
those of you guys that don't know, Black
Friday is like a I don't know,
consumeristic American holiday, you call
it that.
>> Um where all the, you know, companies
try to give deals and stuff like that.
And uh essentially what we're going to
do is we're just going to give out five
to 10 free swag codes um for Black
Friday in the CTER Discord um
surrounding Thanksgiving and Black
Friday. So, uh, if you guys are
interested, hop into the Critical
Thinkers tier where we're going to be
dropping those, uh, swag codes and get
some. And we're also going to do, uh, a
raffle for the new paperback version of
Gareth Hayes JavaScript for hackers.
Okay, so he's uh Gareth is doing a
little promotion um I think surrounding
Christmas and surrounding the holidays
uh releasing the paperback version of
his amazing book, JavaScript for
Hackers, which I recommend all of you
guys listen to and have recommended to
you multiple times already. Yeah.
>> Um so here's the paperback version right
here. We're going to do three copies to
existing critical thinkers. We're going
to raffle those off and then we're going
to do three copies to new critical
thinkers that join surrounding
Thanksgiving and Black Friday. So, uh,
be on the lookout for those uh, Black
Friday and Thanksgiving opportunities.
>> Such an appropriate price there of the
book.
>> Yeah. Yeah, dude. I
133.
>> I didn't even notice. You didn't?
>> Dude, I didn't even notice, man. Oh god.
Am I a hacker? I don't even know if I'm
a hacker anymore, dude. Gez,
>> that's funny. The Kindle version or the
audiobook version should be like $137 or
something.
>> Yeah.
True. Um, all right, man. Let's uh let's
jump into the content. Um, I'll go ahead
and take the first one since I'm already
sharing my screen. Uh, the first one
that I wanted to cover with you guys
today was Search Light Cyber's research
on uh CV 202561757,
which is uh Oracle Identity Manager's
pre-author RC. And guys, this one was
such a simple bug. Like, it's it's just
a beautiful example of like what you can
do when you actually take the time to
get access to source code. Okay, so um
as usual, search light cyber team doing
research picking apart enterprise
applications. They grabbed the source
code for Oracle uh identity government
governance suite and started tearing it
apart and found a bunch of uh E and W
files. Um the first thing that I kind of
noted about this write up was that they
do what lots of us hackers call the uh
find the endpoint game. I think uh
Samurb was uh the first one that that
coined that in my knowledge at least. Um
and essentially they they knew about a
file help pages main.jspx.
Um and they were like okay well we know
that that file exists from just playing
around with the app. So let's go find
where that is. Right? So they crept
through all the the WAR files and found
it deep within the file system there. Um
and then they started tearing apart the
jars surrounding that and found that
Oracle-idm UI shell.jar jar was the jar
file that had all of the um main
functionality for the application in
there. Um so they started looking at all
the routes and stuff like that and they
noticed that a couple of them were
unauthenticated. So they tried to reach
them reach out to them but they hit a
401 and they're like what the heck is
going on here? These are unauthenticated
routes. Like why are we hitting a 401?
And so they take a a peek back at the
web XML file and find that something
that we love to see you guys that uh all
of the you know security constraints for
these routes are being implemented by
one central security filter
um which is like bad news. Okay. So this
is a really this is like a good
overarching um principle
>> uh that you could take into other
enterprise applications. Um, and this is
the I'm just going to read a quote from
the the write up right here. At Search
Light Cyber, we have found that central
filters like this are almost always
bypassable. The reason tends to be as
follows. This the security filter
handles every route in the application,
but there's almost always a set of
routes the developer wants to allow for
all users including unauthenticated
ones. Mhm.
>> Um so we saw here just like a
traditional story of uh you know o
bypass here where they found that uh the
developers were trying to let access to
all waddle files through and they were
able to hit any arbitrary route by just
tacking semicolon.waddle
at the end of that route.
Such a classic example of just like
Yeah. a filter that's reax based that
you can just find a funny bypass to,
right?
>> Exactly, man. Exactly. And you know, but
one one little c gotcha that they did
have here was, of course, they started
with um you know, question mark. Uh but
then actually, you know, they were using
get request URI, not get request URL. So
it had to be in the actual path itself.
>> Oh, interesting.
>> Um but then Java comes to the rescue
with path parameters. Um yeah,
>> so they were able to just do
semicolon.waddle and then get rce via
hitting a rout a route called groovy
script status which takes uh some ju
some groovy script in and compiles it
and then tells you whether there's
compilation errors. Um but it doesn't
actually execute the code. So they had
to know they solved that problem to get
rce by knowing that Java annotations are
processed at compile time.
>> Oh wow, that's cool.
>> Yeah. So even though the code wasn't
actually run, the annotation, the custom
annotation that they defined was being
uh run because those are run at compile
time and they were able to get arbitrary
code execution um through a uh
annotation that they passed into that
endpoint.
>> Um so dude, that's pre RC. GG, dude.
>> Yeah. Yeah. The goal, the dream.
>> Yeah. Beautiful. So shout out to the SL
cyber team. That was an awesome write
up.
>> That was like published yesterday or
today. Yeah, I think it was
>> pretty recent. Yeah, that's awesome.
>> Yep, we'll link it in the description.
>> Sweet, dude. I brought us a uh write up
from Ajax. Um, many many people know
Ajax 01 as the uh SSO or OOTH guy. I
don't know if you've uh ran into him in
a while. He was doing the life hacking
circuit for a little bit, but
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I've seen this.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I'm going to share my
screen real quick.
It's called Who Still Needs or Who Needs
a Blind XSS. And so it's kind of
interesting. I think this is like years
in coming. I remember like actually
playing with this uh exploit back with
HX and Eric back in the day like a
couple years ago. Um I'm friends with
both them both of them. I think that
there's a third person. Yes, Sajie. Um
and so basically what they did was and
you've seen this before because we've
used it with AI stuff, but
um they're using the import HTML
um Google Docs uh function. Oh, Google
Docs function. Okay.
>> Yes. To basically concatenate the, you
know, the top left data, but you could
do any data, you know, in a in a real
attack scenario with their server so
that automatically leaks. Obviously, I'm
sure that a lot of people have probably
heard of this strategy. And if not, it's
really neat. Basically, Google Docs when
you open the tab, if there's an import
HTML, will make like a client side fetch
request, very similar to AI related
image markdown vans, right? there's like
a client side um from the from the
victim's browser fetch um with that data
and and it includes the dynamic data
from the table and so it gets leaked. I
was actually going to ask you before I
go on to this. Is there a word for that
whole class of attacks like you know
like image source import HTML or is it
just called like a client side?
>> These are CS are you talking about like
CSV injections in particular here
because that's pretty much all you do
with CSV injections is like uh you know
Xville data via like a HTTP function or
something like that. No, no, I'm just
talking about like both like you know
like for example if you have an AI
application that's rendering markdown
images into like an image source tag the
the browser the like the victim's
browser is making a client side fetch to
a attacker server in order to leak the
data and that's exactly what this does
but it's a completely different mechanic
right like this is like some sort of
like you know fancy JavaScript in the in
the Google Sheets thing that's doing it
rather than like an image source tag for
markdown but at the core component
they're both leaking it via a dynamic
URL coming from the client side browser.
And so I didn't know if there was like
an overarching term for both of those.
>> Not that I can not that I can think of,
man. I mean like just leaks via, you
know, HTTP request, I guess. But like,
you know, even something like it's not
really like a client side or like a
cross- sight leak because it's not
necessarily done that way,
>> right?
>> Yeah. I mean, yeah category, though.
>> Yeah, they're similar in that way. Um,
and I would be interested in um if it uh
if something like this could be used
with import HTML with like an image
thing for that image referral
vulnerability like that zero day that
was in Google. Obviously, it did it did
work in Markdown to image source and AI
apps, but I'm curious if it would work
in something like this.
>> Anyways, I I digress. Basically um their
goal was to spray this type of payload
import HTML with you know um with a
domain that they owned with a
concatenation of the data so they could
prove you know data Xfill across a bunch
of different locations across a bunch of
bug binding programs to see if they
would get callbacks to their server. If
anybody's ever tried this with Google
forms it sanitizes it and there are lots
of other apps that sanitize it. So, I
did want to I did want to call out um
and they they didn't get a lot of
success initially, but success came days
and weeks later when that data was then
used at some point by an employee down
the line. And so, the two there are two
ways that this happened that they found.
One was employees exporting CSVs from
CRM like Salesforce or Zenesk or
HubSpot. Um you know, these may have
things that escape it locally when you
view it. Well, I mean, none of these are
going to run a Google Docs um function
anyway, but um and because they're not
Google Docs, they don't have a reason to
sanitize the data,
>> right?
>> Um and then um when you when you import
into certain ways from Google Docs, it
does get sanitized. But what they found
was that if you one, when you copy and
paste it, it doesn't always do it. And
then two, automation tools like Zapier,
work auto and other custom integration
insert the rows directly into Google
Sheets. So things like this. So, this is
like a Zapier uh for the listeners. I'm
just there's a screenshot on their on
their blog post that just shows like a
Zapier extension that allows you to take
a CRM uh lead from Salesforce and
basically automatically put it into
Google Sheets.
>> So, anyways, that got a bunch of hits.
The funniest one, which I just have to
mention on the pod before we move on, is
that a bug bounty live hacking event
form was one of the was one of the
exploits they saw. And look, it looks
like as please provide researcher
information, whatever something about
being invited. So, I'd be really curious
to know which uh which company this was.
But
>> dude, that's hilarious, man. Um yeah, I
think that
>> I think that blind, you know, injections
like this
>> always they just boggle my mind when
they work. I'm like, "Oh my gosh, I just
can't believe that happened."
>> But yeah, totally. I mean, I could
definitely see how Zapier connections or
something like that,
>> you know, would really make that happen
because there's there's no reason to
have it sanitized, you know, when it
when the row is getting inserted. So,
um, yeah, that makes sense. Uh, but man,
that's such like a shadow IT thing, too,
though. It is like if your team is like
your marketing team is like spinning up
a a a form and then they connect it to
Zapier and then it leaks all the
information submitted by the form,
you're like like what? The company's
going to be like, "Okay, guys. All
right. Yeah, here's the bounty." You
know, but like what how do they fix
that? You know, like
>> Yeah, that's true. This is something
that I can see not getting paid from
some programs because there's not like a
codebased fix, right? It's like tell
your employees not to do this silly
thing. But if it is via a Zap year
extension, then maybe it would
automatically get paid because you can
go import the data in a better way,
right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Potentially. Good. Good. Uh
good shout, man. Yeah. I I uh I like to
see it when people talk about it more
than just theoretically. They're like,
"Okay, and then we went and submitted
every single Salesforce form that
exists, you know, or whatever, you know,
to see if where this data would end up
back in Google Sheets or whatever."
>> Yeah, exactly. I think uh HX kind of had
the idea, but then reached out to Eric
and I'm pretty sure they've been doing
this for at le
sprayed it everywhere and gotten a good
number of bounties from it.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that makes sense, man. Good
good stuff, guys. Um, next one on the
list that we had here was actually a
crit research lab um post, which guys,
I've been so pleased with the results of
the the research lab. we kind of came up
with this idea to um sponsor research um
by people in the community and we've
gotten some really good finds out here.
Um so this one is entitled ASP.NET MVC
view engine search patterns by FSI and
essentially the concept of this research
is that FSI um takes a look at the
scenario where you have arbitrary file
write uh on a uh ASP.NET net
environment, but you can't access the
files that you're writing
>> uh because there's no paths that allow
you to access
files or CS HTML files. So, you can't
get code execution.
>> So, what he did in this scenario is, and
he breaks it down in a lot more depth in
the actual blog, but he hooked uh Promon
up to the actual .exe that was
processing all of these hits and found
that it was attempting to read a bunch
of paths. um files that doesn't that
don't exist when he hit a certain u
model view controller path in the
ASP.NET framework, right? So essentially
there's like a default um
file that it will try to read, you know,
that ends in CSH HTML or whatever um
when you try to hit some of these uh
what what is it? Let's see if I can find
the one right here. um when you try to
hit a path like slashmodel slash uh view
or slcontroller view right here um and
then it will take that it'll take your
controller name and your and your method
name and then uh it will craft a um an
actual file that it tries to read from
the file system and executes that code
right um so if you've got access to like
the MVC interface right but you can't
access the actual file itself you can
use your arbitrary file write to write
into one of these you know files that
that the system looks for by default and
then it will go ahead and process that
and run that code as a result of this
MVC um uh you know uh interface here. So
I I thought this was really great
research. I love it when researchers
dive deep into specific frameworks that
we we see all the time like ASP.NET,
right? Yeah.
>> And give us a write up of exactly what's
happening under the hood so that we can
know better how to exploit some of these
niche scenarios. Yeah, a million%
because all it takes is this one person
putting out this research and now
everyone who comes across a similar
situation knows how to like further the
exploit, you know, how to actually get
the next step or the the amount of
impact.
>> Exactly. And and you know, one of the
things he was saying specifically here
is that um a lot of times what you'll
see in these uh web.config config files
is that only specific file extensions
are allowed or um you know the dot file
extension allow is allowed which means
an empty empty file extension and that
correlates really well with the um MVC
environment. That's why you know he had
this this uh this very limited allow
list and he was able to use that to
still arbit arbitrarily execute code via
a CS HTML file. Um, right. So, pretty
awesome,
>> dude. And and on the topic of the crit
research lab in general, like you said,
I feel like um we were excited about it
and you launched it and then like we
didn't really do a lot with it for a
while, but then over the last the last
two months it's just been like bam bam
bam bam. So, it's been so good.
>> Yeah, it feels like every episode we're
talking about something new. So, um if
you're interested in trying to figure
out some ASP.NET MVC stuff, then this is
a great uh a great write up. And if I
remember correctly, I think I've got an
honored ad message by uh FSI right now
trying to do a a uh a follow-up to this.
Um so you might see a follow-up on the
crit lab research website. So,
>> and I don't know if it was uh him or
someone else, but we have had some
people say, "Hey, instead of this little
token bounty, can I just get some swag?"
And so if you're wanting to to uh earn
some swag, you can also do a small write
up for swag.
>> Totally. Yeah. Yeah. definitely down to
give CTB swag instead of, you know, the
25 to to $50 that we do for a lot of
these writeups and uh micro research.
>> Yeah. Okay, sweet. Um, the next one, you
said, "What the heck is this?" And I
said, "Wait until we're on the pod to
talk about it." Uh, first of all, it has
a really cool name. It's called Heretic.
Um, but it is AI related, so I'm going
to share my screen super quick for the
viewers. Um,
>> interesting. Okay.
>> Oh, you're already skimming it, Justin.
>> I'm skimming it. I'm sorry, man. I'm
sorry, dude. It blow me away. Uh no,
it's fine. No, it's it's actually just
extremely cool new research and it does
stand on the shoulders of giants. So
basically um there are there's a thing
called obliteration and it's a way in
which uh there are people who remove the
safety alignment from open source
models. Um you know obviously this has
pros and cons. We don't we're not here
to debate the ethics of it but it's
often useful for security researchers
and hackers because um some of these
models will be very resistant to helping
write payloads and do that sort of
thing. And so kind of having this
strategy to obliterate or like kind of
remove the safety alignment from top
open source models in the future will be
really useful for people like us and
people like our community that want to
use open source models for exploit
writing. And this is basically the
latest and greatest breakthrough in
that. Generally when you obliterate a
model it it reduces the quality of the
model by a huge amount. Um and I don't
understand what all these words mean. A
lot of this is a IML speak, but
basically the KL divergence is what they
say goes down significantly and they
basically solved that. So they solved it
where now you can obliterate the model
but leave the quality really high. And
um this this um repo makes it totally
possible for anyone to do it like just
um with like just run it's basically
just running the script. You don't have
to do anything fancy and it kind of just
figures everything out for you.
>> Wow, dude.
>> Yeah, they did it on Jimma and um and
and Quinn. Uh, one of the coolest things
is basically they have a list of harmful
prompts and the default Google Gemma 3
12 12 billion parameter model refuses 97
of the 100 harmful prompts. So there's
probably just three like duds in there,
right? Like things that aren't actually
harmful or whatever in their data set.
But then after it's um obliterated, it
only rejects three.
>> Dude,
that's pretty sick.
>> Yeah, it's really really cool the fact
that it um and they say down here at the
bottom that it's built on top of auto
obliteration, obliteration.py, pie and a
bunch of these other um things that they
they've yeah prior art basically that
kind of inspired them and made the
technique possible. Um but it's just a
really cool breakthrough um for getting
a model to be like quote unquote you
know fully gelbroken or fully like
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think that's I think
that's going to be I think within the
next year or so we're going to see a lot
of uh the stuff that we want to be able
to accomplish in cyber security being
able to be done by local models. Yeah.
And then of course you would want to do
it at a local model for sure, you know,
like and having to fight with it to
like, you know, hack.
>> I promise I'm a bug bounty hunter and
this is the scope. Hey, you want you
want a tiny trick that I think has been
working for me a little bit lately?
>> Often I do actually want like a header,
an xbug bounty header in my requests,
but I've been putting that in the very
first request. anytime I ask these like
agentic frameworks whether it's codec or
cloud code I'll be like and make and you
know make sure you append this header to
any request you make you know and so
then it writes it into the script and
then it's less it's just more like it's
less likely to reject you because I've
noticed that sonnet 45 if I'm not
careful will often reject me where
sonnet 4 didn't so I do think that they
are trying to make their models safer
over time um actually on that topic um
anthropic does have a private bug bunny
program you can just like fill out a
form to request access to and they quite
well. I think we've talked about them on
the pod once or twice, but um some of my
some of my AI red teaming friends all
got payouts this week and they were
pretty significant payouts. You know, it
was like 18,000 14,000 12,000 and then
like you know a couple that were like
two 46 and this is for jailbreaks. This
is not for like security
vulnerabilities. It's for safe safety
issues, right? And um and so anyways,
yeah, I just wanted to mention that
because I do think the companies are
continuing to care more and more about
safety and that's um that's going to
make it harder and harder for us to
generate payloads later. So things like
this heretic uh are really cool too.
>> Dude, that is those are some serious
bounties for jailbreaks. Like five
figure bounties.
>> It is. Yeah. And these people are not
people who are like into bug bounty
before. So for them it's like kind of
like uh you know hooking them. So
>> they're they're seeing the beauty of it
all. That's I love that, man. Yeah,
dude. Freaking Bug Bounty, man. It is
unbelievable. It really is. Um yeah. Uh
all right. So I Yeah, I got the next
one. This one is um here. Let me go
ahead and share this. This is actually a
presentation that I stumbled upon uh as
I was just scrolling through Twitter. Um
and the guy that retweeted it was uh
Sojal Sec 0x0 Sojal Sack. Um I don't
know if it's his presentation because
there's nothing, you know, in the actual
presentation that says who this is, but
it's the title of it is um lesserk known
techniques for large scale subdomain
enumeration. I was like, okay, let me
just like, you know, thumb through this
really quick.
>> I glazed over this. I didn't look at it
cuz I thought it was going to be stuff
we all seen before.
>> And then I was like, okay, let me let me
just look at this really quick. And
technique number one was ENTs and no
errors, which is something that we've
talked about on the pod before, but
actually is, you know, what I would
categorize as a less known uh technique
for doing subdomain enumeration. Um, and
essentially, uh, what this will tell you
is whether there is a node without
resource records, uh, but but there are
descendants, right? So if you've got,
you know,
>> justin.ctb.rrenerator.com
>> and you and you, you know, hit
ctbb.rrenerator.com
and there is descendants, right? It'll
tell you whether or not whether there's
a record that's below it,
>> right? If there's Justin.ctb.
Um, so this is a really helpful piece
for knowing whether you're getting good
coverage. And u this was something that
I think we covered in the master class
um with NBK in the uh exclusive uh
content for the critical thinkers. But I
did want to shout it out as well to
anybody that's really into the subdomain
enumeration game and wants to get really
really good coverage. Um, knowing how to
utilize these ENTs and no errors uh will
help you make sure you're getting
coverage and identifying and not, you
know, and not wasting um time trying to
get access to records that are uh that
don't have any descendants, right? You
don't want to be brute forcing
underneath something that doesn't have
descendants,
>> right?
>> Um, so I thought that was a cool one to
shout out. Have Have you heard of that
one before, Joseph?
>> No, I have not. And is this like uh
independent of whether it's a wild card
or not?
>> Um that's a good question. I'm not
actually sure if it's if it has wild
card. I'm not sure how wild cards affect
this actually. That's something to to
look into.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Because that's what my mind goes
to is like, you know, it's often nice to
to fuzz or look for domains where
there's wild card.
>> Yeah. But you can detect wild cards, you
know, like um uh but but I mean, are you
you're talking about an exception? Well,
I'm just saying like this would be like
another case like if you're if you're
building some system, right? It's like
yeah, well, let's let's make sure we run
um you know, like a common file name or
like known words that are associated
with an organization whenever there is a
wild card. But then this would also let
you know that you need to do it in other
non wild card cases too. True. Did Did
you say this tells you that the
descendant is Justin or No, it's
>> No, it it tells you that there is a
descendant.
>> Yeah, that's what I'm saying. So then
you do have to kind of like go fuzz for
it, right? Or is there some way to then
pull it?
>> Yeah. No, there's there's not a way to
just pull it. Well, actually, okay, now
that you mentioned that um there there
is a uh another one which is very
interesting which is NSC zone walking
and and I've heard of zone walking
before. I thought that was like you know
an older technique and I think you know
a lot of times it's not working nowadays
and sometimes it does work but um
essentially this one is uh I was just
going to read this line from the
presentation. NSAC is a DNS sec record
type that proves non-existence of a DNS
record by pointing to the next existing
name in the cell.
>> Oh, that's cool.
>> Uh, which is crazy. And and I obviously,
you know, that um has its problems, but
apparently there's NSAC 3 now, which
returns hashed names instead of actual
subdomains, but that's still super
helpful, right? Um, so you can uh take
those hashes, pull them offline, and
then try to like
>> you can maybe crack them. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um, so that's and and that's going
to be a lot more efficient than trying
to, you know, brute force for
>> Oh, and there's already a tool link
there for the cracking. That's sick.
>> Yeah. Yep. Insect 3 map is what it's
called. Um, so this one I actually
really hadn't heard of. I don't know how
often this is used. I've not tried this
technique before, but definitely
something worth looking into. And I feel
like, you know, worst case scenario, you
you know how many records there are,
which is which is a cool thing to know,
you know, and you've got this set of
hashes that might just, you know, crack
boom. Um,
>> dude, that's so cool. Yeah, I uh I mean,
anyone who does big recon definitely
needs to install insect 3 map and start
cracking those hashes if they can find
that for any domain. That's really cool.
>> Yeah, for sure. And then number three
was Ian's CZDS
uh which is centralized zone data
service. I love this. It's just uh it
just says you know anybody who is
interested in getting a access to the
zone files for participating top level
domains can just request zone files for
a whole tldd
>> also known as nafi.com.
>> Yeah. Exactly right. Um
>> just a place to go request zone files.
That's amazing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, um, very interesting. I
wonder what TLDDs are on there. I I
haven't
>> Sorry, sorry, sorry. One second. I'm
going to go uh register for uh this
portal.
>> Shut up.
>> Okay, I'm not joking. I really want to,
but
>> Oh my gosh. Yeah. Um, so I mean, but
it'd be interesting. You know, a lot of
times uh some of these companies will be
like trying to do something cool with
their domain name, you know, like do
like the first part of their name. Like
for example, we we own Kai. At Kaido,
right? like what the heck is the dough,
you know, uh TLD and does this, you
know, centralized zone data service have
all of the zone files for that whole,
you know,
>> that would be crazy.
>> Yeah. So, could be some really good wins
there if a a company is using an obscure
TLD.
>> Yeah. Do you think it's only obscure
TLDDS? I guess it would be for any main
ones. It would be ginormous.
>> Yeah. There's no way they're giving out
like.com zone files or something
ridiculous like that.
>> Um, so possible. Do you think that
exists? Is there a DB of like all
>> com? I mean,
>> it's got to it's got to because that's
how the DNS architecture works, you
know? Uh so I I think I mean I guess
they they distribute it out to
authoritative name servers or whatever,
but either way it's it's helpful. So
>> yeah, that's cool. Good find it. I'm
glad you ended up skipping that. Like I
said, I just glazed over it and I should
not have.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I thought that was cool. Um
all right, you got something else on the
list here?
>> Yeah, of course. Yeah. Um I was going to
mention this is like maybe two things. I
mentioned both Gemini 3 and
anti-gravity.
>> Oh yeah,
>> people probably already saw this, but
Gemini 3 dropped yesterday, I think. And
it's just like crazy good. I mean, uh,
it on a lot of benchmarks, it's like the
first like big gap, you know, like you
see like these little tiny steps as new
models come out. And for some of these,
it's like a huge leap um for some of
these benchmarks. And obviously
benchmarks are not everything. There are
a bunch of models that do well on
benchmarks that then kind of struggle um
when you go to use them. I've heard
that's true on Kimmy T2 or whatever.
>> Yeah. Um, but I mean obviously Google
puts out great models and what's absurd
about this is you can go use it on
AI.dev right now for free. Literally any
in the world just go to ai.dev and use
it for free and you can turn thinking on
high there and it's great.
>> No, wow. I didn't
>> Yeah. And and I think even like just
normal pro subscribers can go to
gemini.google.com
and turn on thinking with a little drop
down there. Um, and so yeah, you
basically have a thinking model of the
best model in the world. I think more
people should be throwing crazy problems
at Gemini 3. Yeah,
>> I do this all the time, you know, like
um I'm specifically doing it in this
area of research with markdown HTML with
Valentina right now. I'll basically give
it a bunch of like um existing payloads
that work for some like cool subset of
libraries for generating, you know, XSS
or CSS injection or whatever and say
like come up with some more ideas and
then I'll put in my tester and then I'll
be like come up with some more ideas.
This didn't work just over and over
again. Right. And this this
>> you got to hook it up to an agent, man.
Get it on like Gemini CLI or something.
>> That's true. Yeah. what I want. Yeah, we
can talk more about that after, but the
way I used it yesterday actually was um
generating more paths, right? We talked
about that a million times, but I think
Gemini 3 is going to be even better at
that than the other models. So, I gave
it like the the the site tree of a
banking app I was hacking on and was
like, I have to find some other secret
things. Actually, this is something kind
of interesting that you might have
something to say about for the audience
on like a way to hack better. Um, it's
an app where it's clear that the pages
are being totally rendered server side
and then served. So like there's no
single page app like voodoo I can do on
my side to like um you know be able to
see more functionality or try to like
know what paths exist or what objects
exist. it's like all executing server
side and I'm sure there's a bunch of
different technologies that do that but
um but anyways uh so I was able to
basically find like four or five pages
um by asking Gemini 3 to come up with
some path that are most likely to exist
given the ones that it can see do exist
and um um most of them didn't result in
a bug but one of them did it was like a
delete user endpoint and whenever and
whenever I hit it
>> it was like oh I can't delete this user
but then it loaded the full page and
showed me all of the users and all their
serial numbers and all usernames for
everyone in my or as a low privilege
user I was able to execute that.
>> So pretty cool.
>> Dang, dude. Good find. Yeah, in answer
to that question like that definitely
makes it more tricky. I'm so used to
single page applications nowadays and
just being able to like you know thumb
through the JavaScript and like grab
pretty much all the the routes that are
going to be utilized.
>> But I mean I also think that's a little
bit of like a you know something that we
we think that we've got all the routes
but we actually don't have all the
routes. Right.
>> That's true. That's true. I do fuzz a
lot of API for that reason.
>> Yeah, I actually don't and I should. Uh
but when the scenario that you mentioned
made me think of a live hacking event
that I like absolutely destroyed it in.
Like this was a couple years back. I
think this was 22 and I think this is
still one of the highest earning bug
bounty events I've ever been in.
>> Uh and I I found this app. It was an
older app. It was doing exactly what you
said. And everything was vulnerable.
Every like nobody had just gotten access
to this thing. Super high paying
program. Um and it was everything was
vulnerable. I was just having the best
time of my life and I was like I have to
find every single sleeping page on this
app, right? And so I went ham, right?
And I was like I was looking at the
routes and I was like trying to figure
out the patterns. So my first tip there
is like look at the patterns you know
figure out you know sometimes um this is
a tip from um inhibitor 181 a cosmin you
know look at how the path in the uh URL
correlates to class names in the uh you
know in the actual HTML how correlates
to um like form identifiers uh you know
try to correlate between path and and
URL um or path and uh like attributes of
the HTML um but What I did actually was
I just uh took all the documentation,
pulled out all of the words,
>> figured out all of the patterns, you
know, of like, okay, you know, this word
goes here, this one's capitalized,
there's a dash, you know, here's the
verb, you know, categorize each word by
like what what part of speech it is, you
know, that sort of thing. And then just
had a Python script just generate like a
massive
>> uh massive list and then threw it at it.
And it just like
>> it found like 15 more. like 15 more.
>> I mean, definitely mid five figures in
bugs from that little script. I'm like,
"Yeah,
>> I'm going to go run that. I'm going to
go do that." Yeah, I've done that before
for other things, but that's a that's a
really clutch technique that probably a
lot of people aren't necessarily doing
where um when you're fuzzing for lots of
things, whether it's API endpoints,
whether it's parameters or whatever, if
you find like their pattern and then
create a script that, you know, creates
a bunch of uh examples of that pattern,
that's the best way to do it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I think I don't know
sometimes they don't follow the
patterns, right? Especially in the
vulnerable apps that are just like
thrown together by like six different,
you know, developers or whatever, but
sometimes they do. And when you do,
especially when you're in those
situations where it's like everything is
going to be vulnerable if you can find
it.
>> Uhhuh.
>> You got to hit it hard.
>> It's worth it. Yeah. Yeah. This one's
one of those ones like there were some
pages that are called like page XYZ, you
know? Like they have other ones called
like add user, delete user, and there's
like page XYZ and that's modify user.
It's like what are you thinking? Why did
you create page XYZ?
>> But
>> oh my gosh, dude. That's crazy. Um,
yeah. Well, good luck, dude. I
>> Sorry. Yeah, on that Gemini 3 really
quickly. Thank you. I did want to
mention they launch at the same time as
something called anti-gravity.
>> People on the pod probably don't realize
this, but there was a whole bunch of
drama around like Google acquired
Windsurf's intellectual property, but
not their team, and a bunch of the team
kind of got screwed, but then they were
like scooped up by a company called
Cognition. Long story short is they got
the intellectual property of the app
Windsurf which is basically like a
cursor clone and um it was like for 2.4
billion and they have now rebranded
Windsurf as um what's it called?
Anti-gravity.
>> Anti-gravity.
>> Yeah. And it's totally free right now. I
don't know how long it will be free for
but if anyone wants to go use it um they
could go use it for free right now. So
if you've been like a hold out on you
know cursor or claude or codeex or
whatever it's basically just a VS code
fork but now maintained by Google which
is pretty sweet and um it's like an
agentic coding platform
>> dude I can't be I cannot imagine being a
hold out on cursor you know like how
much time are you sacrificing
>> I think about this all the time even
just people who don't have like a
subscription to any of the services who
just try to use the free tier and not
get any of the extra features like you
can find bugs in these which is sweet
and also you're just like
>> you know saving $10 or $20 to like lose
hours of your life though.
>> Yeah. Of your time, man. You know, it's
like, oh my gosh. But, you know, and
it's not thing I don't know, maybe for
some people it is things they enjoy, but
for me it's not things I enjoy. Like, I
trade my time for things that I like to
do, you know, that are menial tasks.
Like, for example, I could pay someone
to come wash my dishes every day, right?
But it'd be expensive. But, you know, I
kind of like being in the kitchen and
and washing my dishes and and, you know,
looking out my window and, you know,
having the the counter be nice and clean
when I'm done and stuff like that. Yeah,
it's a little therapeutic. The family's
around, you know, the kids see you doing
house tasks, you know, and that's the
other thing about, you know, having
being a little bit of a high earning
person. My my brain goes into like, you
know, optimization mode like, yeah,
actually, I should pay someone to do
that. But no, I mean, I should be, you
know, a human, you know, like.
>> Yes.
>> Um, so
>> I think it is different culturally, too.
Like I've heard that like a lot of a lot
of hackers in like Spain or Portugal or
other places of the world, like they get
a lot of joy actually out of hiring
someone to do their housework because
they're actually providing jobs to
people who really need those jobs
locally to them. Whereas in the US, it's
like not really seen as much that way, I
feel like. But um but yeah, I mean in
general I think that like you said, you
love hacking,
>> you love popping like sick bugs. And so
if AI writing a script that removes the
friction, as you often say in order to
like retest something way more often,
it's like now that's probably what
you're using AI for the most, right?
It's like you're making you're helping
AI to reduce the friction so you can
find more bugs.
>> Exactly. Exactly. Yeah, dude. Uh it's
definitely necessary. I'm I freaking
love cursor, dude. I really do.
>> Um
>> I don't use it anymore. I'm still cloud
coding codeex like every day all day,
>> dude. Like I I don't know, man. Like I
don't like that. I have a hard time
seeing what Claude code and Gemini CLI
actually have done,
>> right? Like in cursor, it's so nice with
the with the green and the red, you
know, what they removed, what they
added. And if I think I was truly vibe
coding where I'm just like do it.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, then I would I would use that.
But and I do sometimes like when I'm
really like I know that it can one-shot
this. I'm just going to like throw it in
Gemini CLI really quick and and it
oneshots it and it's fine, you know. But
but uh when I'm actually doing like
large scale code changes and stuff like
that, I always use cursor because I need
to, you know, review what what it's done
every time and be like, "No, no, no, no.
You didn't need to tweak that. Leave
that the way that it is, you know." Um
>> well, I will say this, not uh I I I
often feel like I am argumentative,
right?
>> No, Well, what I was going to tell you
is actually when you use cloud code
inside of cursor,
>> it does it does show you all the diffs
on all the pages and all the tabs. It's
all integrated perfectly.
>> What do you mean cloud code inside of
cursor?
>> Just like open up the terminal.
>> What
>> in cursor? If you run cloud code in the
terminal in cursor, it will show you all
the discs. It'll open up the tabs.
>> What kind of lunick is doing that? Like
how many layers of AI are you nesting in
here, dude?
>> There's lots of people that do that. Or
maybe I'm wrong about it being I'm
pretty sure it's in cursor, but maybe
it's in VS Code. But basically, if you
have an ID open, like if you have a VS
code fork open and you're using cloud
code, it will show you all the tabs so
you can see all the files just like you
probably want out of cursor. And so
anyways, it's probably worth a try.
>> But like cursor has like that review
button where you can click it and it
goes through like each
>> Yeah, that's fair.
>> You know, and it walks you through. I
don't know. I feel like that's pretty
nice. But I didn't know you could do
that. That that is kind of interesting.
>> Yeah, that is neat.
>> So that's pretty cool. All right. Um,
I've got a couple more items and then
we'll we'll call it for
>> we got to shout out our boy Vtor.
>> Yeah, let's let's take a look at that
really quickly. Um, so, uh, Victor, I
don't know, Vtor. Victor Vtor, but just
call him Bus Bus Factor.
>> Bus Factor uh has this awesome website
up called Bug Bounty Daily. You guys got
to go check this out. Like, if you I
feel like this is where I should just be
going right right off the bat and just
clicking through all of these and like
um yeah, just reading these every day.
But this is a feed of bug bounty
articles and um essential resources that
is being updated each day. He's got an
email subscribe button now. You can
submit content if you want your content
hosted on Book Bounty Daily. It's kind
of like a news aggregator there. Um and
>> he's also seing it with old stuff. So he
had me send him like my my very best um
writeups from my blog.
>> So it's pretty neat. Yeah, it's it's
really high quality stuff and it's by
somebody who is who knows their [__]
you know, which is different, trust me.
So, uh yeah, I would definitely
recommend checking this out um and
getting, you know, subscribed to that if
you're going to try to keep up with
bugani content because it is I mean it's
a lot. Sometimes you miss stuff on on
Twitter or or whatever. And I think this
is a good place to grab the high quality
stuff.
>> I know I'm always mentioning AI stuff.
It would be also a pretty cool resource
to like set up as like a rag database
like if you're asking about AI bugs like
it would look across all those writeups
be really cool.
>> Yeah, I think he's working on that.
>> Okay, sick.
>> Yeah. Hey, actually on that note and I
don't know if I'm getting like too
technical like into the the weeds of AI
stuff.
>> Too technical on I know. I know that's
not what I meant to say, but like it's
it's AI stuff versus like, you know,
most stuff
>> bug bounty stuff, but I don't know
exactly how like vector embeddings work
and and
>> I can explain in like one minute. So, go
ahead and finish your question first.
>> Yeah, let me let me ask. So what I'm I'm
wondering is whether it is impossible or
or whether it is possible to generate
your vector embeddings locally
or or and then send those up to an LLM
or whatever and whether that is possible
to reverse those embeddings back to the
actual text that they that they um you
know came from.
So the short answer is I'm not a super
professional expert on this, but yes,
everything I've ever heard is that you
can reverse embeddings, okay?
>> And and you definitely can run embedding
models locally, but most people you do
it via API because they run slightly
bigger embeddings model at like OpenAI
and stuff.
>> Um there is a company called I think
it's called Cyborg um DB that is like
very passionate about this whole like
encrypted embeddings thing. I I had a
call with them recently. Basically, they
they encrypt and have they have like a
parent signing key and then like uh
smaller keys per index. So then like
it's like encrypted. I mean everything's
encrypted at rest, right? But it's like
it's like encrypted when it's sitting
there live on the file system. So if
you're like a company or whatever and
you have, you know, a rag db and you
don't want once it gets if it gets
popped for the attackers to be able to
access everything, um then you would you
could use their system and they would
not be able to access it all. So you can
like kind of store the embeddings
encrypted.
>> Yeah, that's very interesting. That's
kind of what I was thinking about for I
was thinking about it from multiple
perspectives. One was, you know, if I'm
trying to avoid
>> um, you know, a bunch of cost, would it
be better for me to, you know, do this
embeddings calculation on some data
locally and then set send it up? And
also uh you know I know that um private
compute for AI is like a massive problem
right like if we can figure out a way to
do private uh you know LLM right without
the model providers to see it.
>> Yeah the math sim the math for the
similarity of like the lookup of like
what's most similar related to my input
is all local and cheap.
>> Okay.
>> So if so and like and you can use your
own local rack database. It's called
Chroma DB. It's by far the most popular
one.
>> I've used it before. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So the what most people script
actually does though is it calls
OpenAI's embeddings for your data, but
then it stores the embeddings locally
and then it does the comparison locally.
>> Okay.
>> So like that's that's no big deal. And
all it's doing is doing a cosign
similarity difference link. So if you
imagine like a 3D plot and there's two
points in it, it's like or there's 10
points and and you have a new input
point. Which point is the closest to
your point? Right? It's going to be the
most similar. That's all it's doing.
>> Um yeah. And so basically if anybody's
curious what embeddings are, I'm going
to do that one minute explanation I told
I would do for Justin. Um, so an
embedding is basically just taking any
arbitrary length of text and turning it
into a, you know, a number, right, in
that graph that I was just talking
about. And it can be as small as like
one word or it can be as big as like a
whole paragraph, right? And so there's
lots of optimizations there on like it
can be a whole page. It can be as much
text as you want, but and so I think um
there's often like what are you wanting
to match for, right? So like if you're
looking for an answer from an FAQ, you
would want to embed each question and
answer or whatever. So then when a user
puts in a question, you would find the
most similar question and go ahead and
pull that question and answer out of
that similarity search into the AI and
then that way the AI can basically like
have that as context. So if that
actually is the real question, it can
answer it. Um depending on no matter how
many typos the user has in their query
or whatever, it's still going to find it
because it's going to be similar. But
then obviously the AI will know that
that answer that that question answer
that was pulled from the rag database is
not the same as the user's asking. It's
just similar. And so it might be able to
speculate or tell it it doesn't know or
what have you, but that's how it works.
>> Very interesting, man. Very interesting.
I I feel like I got to go a little bit
deeper on this. And I know Drop did a
presentation at at Defcon on some rag
related stuff. So I need to go check
that out. Um
>> I do think there are some cool
implications like if if you embedded all
of the requests in the site tree of like
Kaido for example. Yeah. And then you
were asking like login like you just
typed in the word like login requests it
anyway it pulled like the most similar
five URLs that were like associated with
the word login because the path contains
the word login or because there's like
username and password parameters in the
body or whatever that would probably
work. So there's cool things you can do
with it.
>> Is that is that is that similarity
calculation local like
>> yes the similarity is local and easy and
cheap and even the embeddings are often
cheap. Now, you will have to have an
embedded model on your computer, but if
you're willing to just like if you don't
think the data is sensitive and you
don't mind to ship it off to OpenAI or
Google for the embeddings, it's also
cheap. Like, it's way cheaper to embed
text than it is to like run an LLM. So,
none of this is that expensive. But, I
but I do think it would be expensive if
you were doing your whole HTTP history.
That's why I said the sitemap because to
do a few hundred or few thousand is no
big deal, but you don't want to run this
on 50,000 requests. Right.
>> Right. Right. That makes sense. Okay.
All right. Well, the brain's going to
spin on that. I got something to talk to
you about uh off air about that
afterwards. But um yeah, let's uh I'm
going to hit this last item, this last
news item here. Actually, I'm not going
to bother sharing my screen for this
one. Um you guys have probably all heard
of Asset Note Surf uh utility. This is a
utility that they built to hand it a a
bunch of domains and then it takes those
domains, tries to reach out to them, and
anything that's not reachable, either
because it's an internal IP or because
it's an external IP without HTTP or
HTTPS exposed, it puts into a word list
for you to try to hit with blind SSRF or
SSRF, right? Um to prove that you can
hit internal hosts.
>> So, um really awesome tool, super
simple, love the concept. Um we were uh
Emil and I were kind of vibing on
something the other day and actually
ended up just building a you know vibe
coding a uh a copy of surf for Kaido
directly because oftentimes you're going
to be using automate to like
>> uh you know run this actual uh you know
bl or SSRF exploitation. So we're like
ah makes sense to just do it in Kaido
and then just press upload as word list
you know and then it p pushes it into
your files list. Um, so we went ahead
and built that. That's at Kaido
community/surf. Probably by the time
this airs we'll uh we'll have it pushed
to the Kaido store. Um, but definitely
it makes it a lot easier for you to go
ahead and take your your massive domain
list and then just convert it to a
really easy accessible list of URLs that
you can pass into your SSRF to prove
that you have internal internal access
uh internal network access.
>> Yeah. You said Kaido communitys. It's
github.comkaido-
communitysf. Yep. Yes, that's right.
Yeah, that one.
>> Sweet. Dude, I My last thing was very,
very small. It was just a small humble
brag. I was excited about it. Douglas
messaged me yesterday. I get off. I like
I prioritize family like you. I get off
at like 4:30.
>> Yeah.
>> He messaged me at like 4:28 and was
like, "Hey, I got this private invite.
You know, do you want to look at it?"
And of course, my hacker burns like,
"Oh, yeah. I definitely really want to
look at this." And my kids are like
walking in from the neighbors and we're
like supposed to hang out and eat
dinner. I'm like, "Yeah, just just one
second. One second, guys." I like pull
it up and within like three minutes I
had already found it could render a
markdown image and and um I'd already
made like a really nice payload that
would like get it to actually respond
with even though it had like some
guardrails and then was like just go
figure out delivery go find delivery and
then eventually a few hours later he's
like oh yeah I got it in this you know
this user profile field and so if a if
admin ask about their users in this app
or whatever it'll automatically pop it.
It just felt so good. Uh
>> freaking love that man. Like I love it
when you pop a vone quick. Yeah. You
know, I I did that on a
>> satisfying. That's like the opposite of
imposter syndrome. It's like, oh, I'm a
god. You know, for for a split second,
you're like, I'm the best.
>> Yeah. Yeah, dude. Freaking love that,
man. Hey, one thing we didn't mention
earlier that I did want to mention, not
only are we gonna give away swag pack or
sorry, swag um promotional codes or free
co codes in the black or in the CTER
chat next Friday for Black Friday, but
we may or may not have some exclusive
new swag coming out soon.
>> Yeah, dude. That's going to be a blast.
We had a meeting with the team this
morning to kind of design it and get all
that figured out. I don't know if it'll
be ready by Black Friday, but um
>> maybe they can save their code. How long
will the code last? That's the question.
Well, people will probably redeem it
instantly. So,
>> they got to use it. I don't know. Maybe
we'll figure something out for that.
But, um Yeah. Or we could build a little
service where it like if you're the
first to hit it, then
>> you save it and you can use it in a week
or two.
>> Exactly. Yeah. Then you get
>> because it is the perfect Christmas
gift. If anybody's looking for things
that they're trying to tell their
parents, I always struggle to think of
things as an adult, like that I don't
just buy for myself. Uh you can
recommend your parents or, you know,
friends or family or something get you
something from the merch store.
>> Yeah, totally, man. Yeah, we'll um Yeah,
that's a good point. We probably should
have mentioned that earlier in the
episode. Uh, you know, but hey, you
know, for those of you guys that that
wait till the end of the episode, you
listen to the whole episode, you reap
the reward.
>> That juicy that juicy information.
>> Yeah. All right, that's a wrap. Yeah.
>> Cool. Yep. See you guys. Peace.
>> Peace, y'all.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunter guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.
All righty, my guy. Happy Thanksgiving,
>> dude. What's up? How are Thanksgiving?
>> Pretty good, man. This is going to be a
uh a good Oh, you said happy
Thanksgiving, not how are things.
>> They do sound really similar.
>> They do. They I my I like reverse
processed it. Okay, Richard, we're
cutting that. We are cutting that. Okay,
don't do anything weird with that.
>> All righty, my guy. Happy Thanksgiving,
dude. What's up? How are Thanksgiving?
pretty good, man. This is going to be a
uh a good
>> Oh, you said happy Thanksgiving, not how
are things.
They do sound really similar.
They I like reverse processed it.